Our coming of age has come and gone.
Folklore: The Long Pond Studio Sessions is a music,
documentary film directed by Taylor Swift.
An intimate concert film, in which Taylor Swift performs each song from her album 'folklore' in order,
as she reveals the meaning and the stories behind all 17 tracks for the very first time.
Self, played by Taylor Swift.
Self, played by Jack Antonoff.
Self, played by Aaron Dessner.
Self, played by Justin Vernon.
Folklore: The Long Pond Studio Sessions (stylized in all lowercase) is a 2020 American documentary concert film directed
and produced by the American singer-songwriter Taylor Swift, released on Disney+ on November 25, 2020.
The documentary is set at Long Pond Studio, an isolated recording studio in a forested area in the Hudson Valley, New York; Swift performs all of the 17 tracks of her
eighth studio album, Folklore (2020), whilst discussing the creative process behind the songs with her collaborators Aaron Dessner and Jack Antonoff.
Swift made her debut as a film director with the documentary, which is her fourth film to be released on a streaming service, following
the releases of The 1989 World Tour Live (2015), Taylor Swift: Reputation Stadium Tour (2018), and Miss Americana (2020).
Receiving widespread critical acclaim, Folklore: The Long Pond Studio Sessions was praised for its music, intimacy, visuals,
and insight provided on Folklore, with many critics labeling the film an admirable supplement to the album.
It received an approval rating of 100% on the review
aggregator website Rotten Tomatoes.
Imbued by the sessions, Swift wrote and recorded several new
songs off-screen while shooting the documentary.
These songs came to be a major portion of Swift's ninth studio album, Evermore
(2020), which was released fifteen days after the documentary.
The film received the Gracie Grand Award for Outstanding Special or Variety.
Accompanying the film's premiere, a live album soundtrack, entitled Folklore: The Long Pond Studio Sessions (From the Disney+ Special),
consisting of the recordings of the live performances featured in the film, was released to music streaming and digital platforms.
The film explores themes of pop star, pop singer, recording
studio, live performance, music recording.